# JERRY **NYUMAH**

Address: 11701 Central Park Way, Maple Grove MN 55369.

Phone: +17634479396.

Email: nuchchelsea@yahoo.com, nuchchelsea95@gmail.com

# **CAREER SUMMARY**

Passionate Restoration Technician with 3+ years experienced performing exceptional tasks on residential and large commercial projects nationwide with Service Master. With my expertise and training in this field, I contributed immensely to the company's growth and success.

2 years of skills in operating a plastic molding machine/plastic extrusion machines, high skills, and safety procedure in operating a sit up forklift. 2+ years knowledge in warehousing and production/manufacturing, packaging, and delivery.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### 04/2021 - Current

DIRECT.SUPPORT.PROFESSIONAL(DSP)&BEHAVIORAL TECHNICIAN Bridges MN, Lino Lake.

- ✓ Assisting individuals with daily living functions.
- ✓ Assisting individuals with bedtime routines, administering medications etc.
- ✓ Supporting individuals in preparing meals and/or snacks.
- ✓ Supporting individuals in cleaning and laundry.
- ✓ Assisting individuals in accessing the community and participating in recreation and leisure activities.
- ✓ Using de-escalating techniques to calm high behavior clients when agitated.
- ✓ Maintain a clean and healthy environment.
- ✓ Document any changes in clients' conditions in the client chart and communication log. Report these changes to the Residential Supervisor.
- ✓ Completes incident reports according to policy.
- ✓ Understands procedures regarding home care tasks and charting procedures when performing these tasks.
- ✓ Recognizing abnormal signs and symptoms, or changes in clients' condition.
- ✓ Documenting duties completed with clients on the service delivery record during each shift.

#### 02/2021 - Current.

BRADLEY VEHICLE SYSTEM MAINTENANER, Department of Defense USARMY. Stillwater MN.

# **DUTIES/TASKS**

- ✓ Troubleshooting and diagnosis on track vehicle
- ✓ Preventive maintenance and control services (PMCS)
- ✓ System maintenance.
- ✓ General maintenance.

03/2019 - 02/2021

SUPERVISOR, SRM/DSI. 8450 COLE PKWY, SHAWNEE, KS 66227.

- ✓ Accomplishes department objectives by supervising crews and organizing and monitoring work processes.
- ✓ Implement and enforces systems, policies, and procedures. Maintaining safe and healthy work environment by establishing and enforcing organization standards and adhering to legal regulations.
- ✓ Provides quality service by enforcing quality and customer service standards.
- ✓ Contributes to team effort by accomplishing related results as needed.
- ✓ For example, helping to mix cleaning chemicals/products following the MSDS or company regulation for a better job result.
- ✓ Work with other employees to ensure teamwork and success is realized.

#### 11/2017 - 03/2019

#### RESTORATION TECHNICIAN, SERVICE MASTER RESTORE. MAPLE GROVE, MN.

#### **DUTIES/TASKS**

- ✓ Proficient in water restoration, mold remediation, and fire damage cleanup.
- ✓ Respond to water jobs and initiate water mitigation according to IICRC standards.
- ✓ Maintaining all company restoration and cleaning equipment, keeping them clean and properly maintained and ready for the next job.
- ✓ Conduct inventory and load the work vehicle with equipment, products and supplies needed for each project, prepare rooms/ areas for work activities, setup staging area and equipment for each project.
- ✓ Ensuring clear two way-way communication with crew chief and other technicians to understand customer needs and concerns.
- ✓ Carpet cleaning, park out, park back, content cleaning, and setting up containments etc.

# 06/2018 - 9/2018

**TEAM MEMBER, BOSTON SCIENTIFIC. MAPLE GROVE, MN 55311** 

- ✓ Assembly of medical parts, inspecting that quality parts are produced.
- ✓ Builds product by following all processes in which certified (in their most current revision), and completing other assigned work, while meeting manufacturing goals and metrics.
- ✓ Maintains accurate records, including training files and shop floor paperwork.
- ✓ One key component and responsibility is the primary focus to build product by following processes to meet production goals.
- ✓ Binding micro beans, and inspecting parts produced in the clean room.

#### 10/2017 - 12/2017

## PRODUCTION CREW MEMBER, AEROTEK STAFFING. BROOKLYN CENTER, MN

## **DUTIES/TASKS**

- ✓ Food production which with emphasis in macaroni cheese, spaghetti etc.
- ✓ Palatizing finished product, sorting, issuing label to finished goods, wrapping and monitoring production belt.
- ✓ Making sure the production floor is Kept clean and safe from hazards.
- ✓ Working together in team following production procedures for good and quality result.

#### 08/2017 - 10/2017

MILLLER/PREP, ATLAS STAFFING, BROOKLYN PARK MN

- ✓ Manufacturing/molding delicate components for companies like Boeing. Made from steel, aluminum blocks titanium etc.
- ✓ Prepping of steel, plastic, bras, cooper, aluminum blocks for parts molding.
- ✓ Production machine Die setting and operation.

#### 09/2016 - 08/2017

#### PLASTIC MACHINE OPERATOR, ADVANCE EXTRUSION INC, ROGERS, MN

## **DUTIES/TASKS**

- ✓ Operates plastic extrusion machine, ensuring quality plastic is produced.
- ✓ Maintaining and controlling functions to ensure line is running efficiently and normal.
- ✓ Conducting inventory or check line at shift change and end of shift.
- ✓ Work order execution and prompt work report submission to the supervisor at the end of the shift.
- ✓ Loading and unloading trailers with finish products with sit up forklift.
- ✓ Use of forklift to complete tasks on production floor as per the work order.

**02/2016 – 06/2016 BACK LINE COOK, HARDEE'S.** 8405 HAMPTON BLVD, NORFOLK, VA 23505.

#### **DUTIES/TASKS**

- ✓ Cook burgers, fries, making scramble eggs on the grille.
- ✓ Maintaining cleaning environment and providing good customer service.
- ✓ Preparing salads and mixing Doug getting it ready for biscuit baking.

# 10/2015 – 12/2015

PRODUCTION TEAM MEMBER, LE BUS BAKERY OULET. 479 SHOEMAKER RD, KING OF PRUSSIA, PA 19406.

- ✓ Contribute to the measuring and mixing of Components/Ingredient for the DOUG.
- ✓ Fill production belt with Doug plates and control it safely to storing FACILITY and baking ovens.
- ✓ Maintain quality production of bread and ensuring clean ENVIRONMENT. cutting, sorting, and packaging of finished product.
- ✓ Preparing different kinds of veggies and meat for pizzas production.

#### 02/2105-07/2015

TEAM MONITOR/ CREW CHIEF, LIBERIA NATIONAL RED CROSS. Monrovia, Liberia.

## **KEY DUTIES/ TASKS**

- ✓ Identifying natural disaster affected areas and take record of victims.
- ✓ Reaching out to victims of Ebola epidemic survivors and families.
- ✓ Aiding victims of the deadly epidemics with food and non-food items supply.
- ✓ Monitoring or supervising food distribution process and making sure beneficiaries receive the right ration allocated.

## 01/2011-01/2012

ADULT LITERACY FACILITATOR, SAMARITAN'S PURSE INTERNATIONAL RELIEF. Foya district Lofa county, Liberia.

## **KEY DUTIES/ TASKS**

- ✓ Teaching and evaluation for older folks who were not fortunate to have achieved early education in towns and villages around the district.
- ✓ Sensitizing and creating awareness to community dwellers about health hygiene, women's right, child labor, family management and preventive measures against communicable diseases.
- ✓ Making sure learning environment is conducive and friendly to encourage learning.

# 01/2013-02/2014

DIRECT SUPPORT PERSONNEL / CARE GIVER, JOHNSONVILLE TRAUMA FACILITY. JOHNSONVILLE, MONROVIA LIBERIA.

## **KEY DUTIES/ TASKS**

- ✓ Assisting clients with daily personal tasks, including bathing, grooming, and dressing
- ✓ Completing housekeeping tasks such as sweeping unit, washing dishes and tidying.
- ✓ Helping plan client appointments and organize a scheduled for hospital visits.
- ✓ Organizing with transportation arrangements to and from appointments
- ✓ Shopping for groceries, household items and preparing meals that meet specific client dietary needs.
- ✓ Encouraging client engagement in social networks and communities.
- ✓ Entertained clients with games, songs, and stories.
- ✓ Monitor and make sure clients are always save and unharmed.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### 07/2021

BRADLEY FIGHTING VEHICLE SYSTEM MANTAINER. DIPLOMA. FORT BENNING, GEORGIA

07/2020 - CURRENT

**SYSTEM SUPPORT ADMINISTRATOR, ASSOCIATE** RASMUSSEEN COLLEGE, BROOKLYN PARK CAMPUS.

FRESHMAN IN COLLEGE

10/2019

#### **OSHA CERTIFICATION.**

30 HOUR GENERAL INDUSTRY SAFETY AND HEALTH

11/2010

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA, VOINJAMA MULTILATERAL HIGH SCHOOL. LIBERIA, WEST AFRICA

Obtained regular high school courses.

# **SKILLS**

- D.O.T Certified
- Drives company F650 box truck, Penske rental truck, nationwide to delivered supplies.
- Operates a sit-up forklift perfectly.
- Able to operate a boom lift, scissor lift and bob cat heavy duty machine.
- Operate an extraction machine/ Truck mount for cleaning carpet and other water extraction purposes.
- Perfect in cleaning glass windows, glass doors etc.
- Build up containments to set negative air pressure for structure drying.
- Computer trouble shooting, maintenance and upgrade.
- Operate multiple hand power tools like chain saw, kett saw, power drill, Sawzall, circular saw etc.

#### **REFERENCES:**

- ✓ NYREEN, JEFFERY R, SFC USARMY NG MNARNG (USA). (320) 616-2758
- ✓ MARIAH JUELICH BRIDGESMN (651) 587-3287
- ✓ KELLY, KURT. SERVICE MASTER MANAGER (651) 755-8734
- ✓ ATLAS STAFFING AGENCY. BROOKLYN PARK MN. (763)400-7643
- ✓ LUIS

  SHIFT SUPERVISOR, ADVANCED EXTRUSION INC. INDUSTRIAL BLVD ROGERS
  (763)772-8910

With expertise, procedures and trainings from previous jobs, the above positions can be well executed with no flaws when offered the position.

This skills and training can be integrated in a workplace to train other employees to boost the company productivity.